

contact@scottvincent.ca

Story

Interface Designer with work that has reached over 1 billion pageviews.

Experienced in graphic design, product design, user interfaces, front end development, and quality assurance testing. I strive for users to love the results as much as I do. I believe putting care into the finest details along the way results in a final product that exceeds expectations.

Specializing in user interface design, it's about keeping things simple and predictable. Finding all the use case scenarios and coming up with clever solutions to them.

In secondary school, I started to familiarize myself with Adobe Photoshop and Final Cut Pro. This led me to completing a two-year TV Broadcasting course at H.B. Beal S.S.

The fun I had with video shooting & editing almost landed me in Fanshawe's TV Broadcasting diploma, but I decided I wanted to try something new: I began a two-year diploma in Multimedia Design and Production at Fanshawe College. After completing this, I entered Music Industry Arts to take my love of music to the studio setting. I've been lucky enough to have learned from some talented professionals, gaining valuable knowledge and building my creativity in all realms.

During my professional career, I worked on many projects in a wide variety of industries. Staying on top of current web trends and technology has been the key to continued success. I have experience in the following areas:

LANGUAGES

HTML5, CSS, Javascript, PHP, C# .NET.

LIBRARIES

LESS, SASS, JQuery, ReactJS, AngularJS, AMP, Cordova, Bootstrap, Google Material Design, Carbon Design System, Font Awesome, and Icomoon.

SOFTWARE

Speed and efficiency in programs such as Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD, Avid Pro Tools, & Apple Logic Pro.

Being able to do anything that is necessary in a project gives me the flexibility to keep the job fresh and interesting.

Experience

tbk Creative

2016/11 - PRESENT

INTERMEDIATE FRONT END DEVELOPER

London, ON

Built front end designs, interactive elements, and accessible web sites using WordPress and WPBakery Page Builder.

IES Group Inc.

2011/4 - 2016/10

GRAPHIC DESIGNER / FRONT END DEVELOPER

London, ON

Design & develop web application interfaces (UI), user experience (UX), logo illustration, branding materials, & marketing collateral.

OUR Coffee News

2009/1 - 2011/7

GRAPHIC / WEB DESIGNER

St. Thomas, ON

Update and maintain website, create ad samples to be placed in the weekly restaurant publication. Setup and print editions with one colour process.

Education

Music Industry Arts

2008 - 2010

FANSHAWE COLLEGE

London, ON

- School of Contemporary Media Diploma
- 2009 MIA Award, Best Performance

Multimedia Design & Production

2006 - 2008

FANSHAWE COLLEGE

London, ON

School of Contemporary Media Diploma

H.B. Beal Secondary School

2002 - 2006

London, ON

- OSSD Diploma, Ontario Scholar
- 2006 Most Co-operative Student Award
- 2005 Skills Canada Video Challenge, Ontario Bronze Medal

Web Projects

Diply

Diply is an entertainment website that I worked on from 2013 to the end of 2014. Created initially as an online product showcase, it morphed into articles to be shared on social media.

Half of the two-man team that built the initial site with Bootstrap 3, and leveraging LESS css, Diply was an AngularJS web application with a custom content management system. I was the Lead UI Designer during the site's first year, responsible for prototyping, front-end styling, and user experience. From launch over the next year I was there, those pages were viewed over 1 billion times.

Project at IES Group Inc.

Media Sonar

Media Sonar is a social media monitoring tool used for public safety and law enforcement. I was a part of the project from 2013 to 2016. After working on the first version of the application briefly in 2013, I was brought on as the Lead Designer for the version 2 refresh at the end of 2014. Prototyping, designing, and styling the front-end for a positive user experience.

An AngularJS web app, Bootstrap 3 was the base styling framework used to build it fully responsive to fit any screen size. Using Google's Material Design Guidelines as a starting point, eventually the design language transformed away from that core to meet the needs of the business. Utilizing LESS css, I created a variable styling structure that allows multiple colour themes for users to switch between, as well as modular components for fast prototyping and delivery.

Project at IES Group Inc.

3M Channel Partner Portal

The Channel Marketing Portal for 3M Canada is an asset repository for all of their partners to use. The intention was for users to have a self-serve way to gather their files and documents rather than requiring manual customer service. Starting with a simple wireframe and 3M's branding guidelines, I led the frontend direction for the user's experience of finding, bundling, and downloading their logos, ads, or sell sheets.

Built with ReactJS, SASS, and utilizing WordPress as an administrator dashboard. A custom theme on top of the Carbon Design System v9 was used for the basis of the frontend framework.

Project at tbk Creative.

G₂PO

A gaming video site that gave users options to search and follow video creators or specific game titles and view videos on the site. I was on the team as a designer and a front end developer through the evolution of two distinct versions in 2011 and 2014.

Responsive for mobile web use, built with Bootstrap 2 and C# .NET.

Project at IES Group Inc.

Branding

Crafting Brands & Branding Crafts

I enjoy designing & constructing new images in Adobe Illustrator, whether it is for startups, bands, or even recreational sports teams. The items below are a collection of logos I've created.

When a major brand makes a change, I'm immediately dissecting what they've done and why. I will read branding blogs daily to see what companies are doing and what the design community thinks of current trends. I usually pick apart when brands are being misused in the wild and get excited when brands nail it.

Also, below are a couple of branding guide PDFs I created to help with styling the projects that I was developing at the time. The first one using the existing Media Sonar logo that wasn't one of my creations, refining it and forming a guide around it. The second one for Pathogent, a project that didn't proceed further than the concept stage.

Music

Audio Engineer, Music Producer, & Musician

I started playing guitar at 10 years old; I would go on to perform in the rock bands Violet Fuse & Duelling Sledgehammers. I'm perpetually working on new compositions and recordings, with a new record in the works.

I graduated from Music Industry Arts at Fanshawe College in 2010, gaining proficiency in Avid Pro Tools, Logic Pro, Avid D-Command interface, analog recording consoles, and music production techniques. I have experience with live music in small venues, as well as sound reinforcement and lighting tech in a theatre setting. While never a career, I've spent a number of years writing, performing, producing, engineering, mixing, and mastering.

This document was generated from printing a webpage.

Visit **scottvincent.ca** to view complete portfolio and examples.